You did it!
Subaru, that was amazing!
Whoever thought this up was evil!
Huh? That's your first reaction?
There's no way that's fair!
Why give questions only people who
know the same sky I do can answer?!
Your master must have been a real jerk!
Aw, c'mon! How can you say that?
You shouldn't say mean
things about yourself!
That aside, this sure is a lot of books.
I'm so curious to see what
kinds of books they all are.
Miss Shaula described this as
a treasure trove of wisdom.
Based on her reaction,
this is the first time she's
seen this archive opened.
We'll have to walk around and
check everything, I suppose.
But it was you who solved
the riddle, right, Subaru?
So is it all right for anyone
other than you to touch them?
Oh, yeah...
But if they made it so only the one
who answered it can read anything,
why would the rest of
you been allowed to enter?
Oh, I get it.
The fact that we got in here at all
probably means we're allowed to be.
Oh, look!
The letters are moving around!
I can't read them at all!
This one's doin' the same thing.
It's a form of cognitive obstruction.
But I can read the titles, I suppose.
This one says "Noah Libertas."
This one says "Aegon Voller."
They're not in any kind of order, either.
Is it possible those are people's names?
Yes, it looks like they are... but...
At a glance, I don't see
any names I recognize.
Of course, that may change if I go
around looking at them all, but...
Damn it...
What's the point in a bunch
of books no one can read?
Hey, isn't this...
Subaru?
A woman.
There was a lone woman.
One so young that I'd hesitate to
call her a "woman," but a woman.
Typhon, let's go.
Her world was all black and white,
good and evil, righteous
deeds and wicked deeds.
And the one who divided them
up so clearly was her father.
He was in charge of dealing criminals
punishments befitting the
gravity of their crimes.
He was the scale that decided what
was good or evil in their world.
He tried to teach that to her,
but she didn't understand.
There was no simple answer
to judge good versus evil.
Crime and punishment were influenced
by many different factors.
And then...
Huh?
I-I'm sorry, Father. I dropped it...
and it broke.
You were right to confess
to your crime and apologize.
That was when she finally understood.
The scale that weighed
the gravity of a crime
could only be found within the
heart of the one who committed it.
Did you do something bad?
Huh?
Are you an evildoer?
Did you do something bad?
Father, are you an evildoer?
Typho—
She understood, and she was content.
She had at last acquired the scale.
The Witch of Pride went on
to question people's sins,
deal punishment, and judge criminals.
Subaru!
Are you all right?
You looked like you were in so much pain.
D-Did I manage to avoid
getting carried off by it?
I'm still here, right?
Typhon...
Is that a name you know, I suppose?
Y-Yeah.
Hey! Are you nuts?!
Now, that's just rude.
It's no different from the
other books, I suppose.
But it appeared differently to you.
That's how I perceived it.
Yeah... but why only this book?
Where did you hear
about this Typhon person?
It's hard to explain.
I mean, if you don't know her,
that means you didn't meet her...
but it was at the graveyard.
The graveyard?
One of the witches who
existed in the past.
The Witch of Pride.
About as young as Beako,
but with darker skin.
But she was like the living
manifestation of innocent cruelty.
I was able to read that book and
experience her... memories? Life? Roots?
Whatever it was, I experienced
them vicariously.
It sure didn't feel good, though.
You experienced someone's
memories... vicariously?
This is sounding more and more
like the trial in the graveyard.
Yeah, except that time, you were
facing your own memories head-on.
That was a piece of cake, though!
R-Right! A piece of cake!
Your tough act aside,
this book lets you experience
someone's memories vicariously.
Put another way, it could be a means
of retracing the past, I suppose.
So the claim that you can find anything
you want to know in this library is—
Julius?!
Julius, keep it together!
You can hear me, can't ya?!
Lady Anastasia...
Yes, that's the way.
Just take slow, deep breaths.
You're gonna be fine.
Got a fever from trying too hard
to read these impossible books?
Look at you, trying to be clever!
Hey, ow!
Don't be mean!
Julius, are you sure you're all right?
Yes. I'm very sorry for worrying you.
That said, it wasn't particularly
good for my own heart.
Wait, you mean... you saw it, too?
Yes.
Balleroy... Temeglyph?
Wasn't there a general with that
name in the Vollachia Empire?
A former general, to be precise.
He was a virtuous warrior
of unparalleled skill.
I faced him one-on-one
and somehow survived,
but only by a hair's breadth.
I knew it.
The books in here can be read by
one familiar with their author—
one who has passed, at that—and grant a
vicarious look into their past, I suppose.
That seems like a fair assessment.
Wouldn't that mean all
the books in this library
are labeled with the names of all dead
people in the world, past and present?
If that's right,
it's gonna take forever to find the one
book about someone you're lookin' for.
Whoever made this library really
was the biggest jerk ever.
Boy, this all feels so overwhelming.
Between this and the riddle,
are you finally interested
in being part of this now?
I'm not sure about that.
But basically, the more
dead people you know,
the more of these books
you can read, right?
There might be quite a
few of them for me, then.
Books of the dead, huh?
You're such a terrible man, Big Brother!
That's a lot more painful coming from you
than it would be from Ram or Anastasia.
This might be a weird time,
but can I ask you some
questions about yourself?
Huh?
I think you have a few too many
romantic interests already.
That's not what this is about, okay?!
I'm just kidding.
If there's something you
wanna know, go ahead and ask.
I'll take you up on that, then.
How long have you been an assassin?
It's been five or six years
since I started this job.
But in my case, it wasn't so much a job
as just following the orders of
my mom, the one who took me in.
Hang on... Are you saying...
Oh, yeah, I was dumped as a child.
I was abandoned in some forest before
I was even old enough to be aware,
and the mabeasts there raised me.
There are mabeasts that
would raise a human baby?
Not normal babies.
But I was born with the
ability to befriend mabeasts.
I guess that saved my life.
In fact...
I think my divine protection was
the reason my family dumped me.
Kinda hard to tell if it was
a good or bad thing, y'know?
Hey, Meili, I'm just being
hypothetical here, but...
What?
If your parents' books were in
here, would you want to read them?
My parents?
As in, not my mom, but my real parents?
Yeah.
No interest at all.
Really?
Don't get the wrong idea about me.
I'm not mad at them for
dumping me or anything.
They're not even worth that, really.
So...
if I'd said I was interested,
what would you have done?
I would've looked for them, of course!
It might not happen right away,
but if you look into it and find
their names, I could make time to—
You really are an idiot, aren't you?
Why, though?!
Say, I was thinking...
How do these books grow in number?
For example...
if you were to drop
dead right here and now,
would your book just appear
out of thin air?
Now that piques my interest!
Sorry, but I can't exactly
test that for your sake!
Sounds like you two are having fun.
Did you find something?
Unfortunately, no.
How about you guys?
No. I'm sorry.
We've had a look around,
but we can't discern any sort of order
in the way the books are arranged.
They're certainly not
ordered by name or date.
In other words,
we found out that we still
don't understand a thing.
So in the end,
this archive is more than
we can deal with right now.
Yeah.
Even if we try our hardest
to find a name we know,
that person might not even
have the information we want.
That makes this very difficult.
In that case, we may be better off
taking the next exam for
entry into the second level.
I agree.
But where is the stairway
leading to the next floor?
Yeah, I don't see one anywhere.
Considering the jerk who built this,
finding the stairway might
be part of the exam.
Jerk?
Shaula!
Come here a sec!
Master! Gotcha! I'm on my way!
What's up? What's up? What would
you like me to do, Master?
When you come up to me with
your eyes sparkling like that,
it makes me feel bad...
Do you know where the stairway
to the second floor—
Nope!
I've never gone higher
than the fourth floor.
In 400 years? That's really surprising.
Shaula, can I ask ya somethin'?
You're the keeper of this
library—of Pleiades, aren't ya?
Exactly!
I see. Then my guess would be...
Four... no, maybe five?
The number of secret rules you were
given for protecting this tower.
It's five, ain't it?
Rules?
And they're secret? What does that mean?
I-It's not like that, Master!
I'm not hiding anything from you!
I just didn't mention it
'cause you didn't ask!
I wanna get that in writing!
Whatever! Just spill it!
Well... just as one example...
if you tried to leave this
tower without telling me,
I'd show no mercy in killing you.
Well, that's quite a leap!
It's not like I want to kill you!
It's just an example!
Besides, it's just something
I can't get around, ya know?
It's so exhausting.
If you hate it that much,
can't you refuse to...
Wait, you're not gonna tell me
you have a contract, are you?!
Are you a spirit like Beako?
Of course I'm not!
Don't go comparing me to flaky
little things like fairies!
I am absolutely not...
You all look really scary suddenly!
Well, about 80% of us here
have connections to fairies.
But if that's not it, then what are you?
If you're not a spirit, why do you have
to cling so desperately to a contract?
What are you saying, Subaru?
Huh?
Even if she's not a spirit or spirit user,
of course she still has to keep her word!
Okay, that was my bad, but it
was just a figure of speech...
Promises are important! And... go!
Promises are important.
Damn it, I got yelled at by Emilia-tan!
This is all your fault!
Spit it out already!
Wow, that's a heck of a false accusation!
That's my master for ya! Okay, I'll talk!
I will now give you a simple explanation
of the orders I was given!
First, I can't let any challengers to the
Great Pleiades Library go back outside.
Okay, so we're stuck right off the bat.
However...
if you pass all the exams and reach
the first floor, it's no problem.
All okay!
Also, if anyone violates these terms,
I'll transform into a heartless
killing machine instantly,
so my promise to you will be voided.
I'll have to harm you.
That ranks higher than your
promise to me? That hurts.
Wow! I managed to hurt my master!
I guess I've leveled up!
No doubt about it! I've evolved!
It was sarcasm!
So was mine.
Moving on...
I'm bored now, so I'll make this quick.
One: leaving before completing
the exams is forbidden.
Two: violating the rules
of the exams is forbidden.
Three: disrespecting the
archive is forbidden.
Four: any action intended to
damage the tower is forbidden.
Five... uh...
There's no five!
So there are four rules... but...
The one about violating the rules
of the exams is bothering me.
It seems likely that there are
hidden rules we don't know about.
You're sure that's the last of 'em?
Everything else is fine, right?
I swear. No lie this time.
Also, as long as none of
those rules are broken,
my body belongs to me!
Oops! I mean it belongs to my master!
Don't want it.
Aw, he sent me back!
But my heart belongs to you forever!
Don't want that, either.
Still, if we can't leave unless
we pass all the exams...
It really is a lot like the
trial at the graveyard.
Nah, if it comes to it, we can
leave if we defeat her, right?
It's easier than the graveyard.
My master would never do that!
He was kinder and more
big-hearted than anyone else!
Oh, crap! Lying made me all itchy!
Okay, go, Meili!
Keep a tight hold on Shaula's reins!
You can count on me!
You know, I've been
thinking a little bit...
about how the one who built this
tower wasn't a very honest person.
The way you phrased that was
adorable, but you're right. And?
Well, about the location
of the stairway...
Could it be that...
See?! There they are!
Yeah, whoever made this
tower was absolute scum.
I'm impressed you figured
it out, Lady Emilia.
Well, it wasn't on the third floor, right?
So I figured it had to be in
a place we've already been.
So this stairway hasn't actually
been here all along, has it?
It may have also been hidden using a form
of cognitive obstruction, I suppose.
Okay, then. Let's take this
thing on and finish it up.
Here we go, Beako!
Hey!
Subaru, wait!
Stop, I suppose!
Stop!
Another white room, huh?
I suppose.
This again?
If this is the second
floor I was expecting...
The exam should start now.
That'll be the trigger, I suppose.
I'm guessing that's supposed to
be some kinda sword of selection.
Here I go.
Fool who has attained the heavenly sword,
earn his pardon.
E-Emilia...
I know.
Fool who has attained the heavenly sword,
earn his pardon.
earn his... pardon...
Huh?
Fool who... heavenly sword... pardon...
What is this? What's gonna happen?
Master! Master! Master! Help!
Shut the hell up!
I've got a hangover,
and my head's pounding!
Quit your screeching!
You gotta be kidding me...
I can see that you are no ordinary man.
Huh? Who the hell are you?
And where am I, anyway?
You messing with me or what?
No, I most certainly am not.
You suddenly appeared before us.
Please understand that we
can't help but be wary.
The hell's your deal?!
Don't talk like my follower!
You my follower? I didn't think so!
So quit making everything so
damn complicated, asshole!
Hot chick. Hot chick.
Sexy chick.
Brat. Brat. Follower. Wuss.
I apologize, but I am not your follower.
Hah! You're sounding more and
more like my follower, though!
Quit imitating him!
Well, let's get started.
Hang on! Would you just slow down?!
Shut your trap! I just explained
everything to you in sleep talk!
You oughta learn to listen!
What are you talking about?
"Fool who has attained the
heavenly sword, earn his pardon."
Hah! This hot chick's way
ahead of the wuss!
Hey, now that I get a closer
look, you're really hot.
The hell's with that face?
It's way too radiant!
Radi—
You're the examiner this time!
Am I right?!
Dunno. I don't give a shit what
labels other people give me.
If you wanna have a conversation with me,
try and get me to move
one measly little step.
I am Julius Juukulius of the
Lugunica Imperial Knights.
I ain't got no name to give.
I'm just...
Stick Swinger
a stick swinger.